### **Eliott Davidson**

Seattle WA | 206-437-8634 | eliott.davidson@gmail.com LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/eliott-davidson/ | GitHub: www.github.com/fussypuppet

### **Summary**

Software engineer in training with a background ranging from mail delivery to biology research to social work. Whether it is answering unknowns about cellular function, delivering the most mail in the shortest time, translating confusing documents into approachable language, or designing code, I'm driven by a desire to distill complicated problems down to their core issues and deliver value, clarity, & efficiency.

### **Technical Skills**

Languages: JavaScript, Python, Typescript, HTML, CSS

Frameworks: React, Node, Express, NextJS

**Databases:** MongoDB, PostgreSQL **Other:** Git, MS Office, Illustrator

--

## **Software Development Experience**

Full-stack web development trainee General Assembly Seattle, WA Completed immersive web development training program involving over 500 hours of experience creating full-stack applications using JavaScript and Python.

# **Professional Experience**

United States Postal Service	City Carrier Assistant	Mercer Island, WA	2017-present		
Lyft	Driver	Seattle, WA	2019-present		
self-employed	Housing Cooperative Treasurer	Seattle, WA	2007-present		
Kaplan Test Prep	Instructor / Course Administrator	Seattle, WA	2015-2016		
Taught classes on standardized test-taking skills for the GMAT exam.					
University of Washington	Post-Doctoral Fellow	Seattle, WA	2014		
University of Utah	Lab Technician	Salt Lake City, UT	2005-2006		
TURN Community Services	Instructor	Salt Lake City, UT	2003-2005		

Taught basic life skills to and advocated for adults with developmental disabilities

#### **Education**

	Software Engineering Immersive Program	General Assembly	Seattle, WA	
	Full stack web development (React, JavaScript,	Python, Postgres, MongoDB)		
	PhD, Molecular & Cellular Biology	University of Washington	Seattle, WA	
construction & function of naturally-occurring molecular machines using computer-assisted pattern				
recognition. Developed methods of informatively displaying and interpreting patterns in unconventional				
	datasets			

BA, Biology University of Utah Salt Lake City, UT